Gerald R. Gill Papers MS170
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Teaching materials, 1978 -- 2007; MS170.007; 24 Linear Feet 20 record cartons
  - Tufts courses, 1980 -- 2007; MS170.007.001; 10.3 Linear Feet 8 full record cartons, 1 partial record carton
    - The African American in United States History Since 1865, HST 96, circa 1984 -- 2007; MS170.007.001.031.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - The African American in United States History Since 1865, HST 58, Spring 1990; MS170.007.001.031.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - The African American in United States History Since 1865, HST 96, Spring 1997; MS170.007.001.031.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - The African American in United States History Since 1865, HST 96, 2003 -- 2006; MS170.007.001.031.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - America in the Nineteenth Century, HST 53, Fall 1981; MS170.007.001.031.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - America in the Twentieth Century, HST 87, Spring 1996; MS170.007.001.031.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - The American Homefront During World War II, HST 187 GG, circa 1995 -- 2005; MS170.007.001.031.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - The American South Since 1865, HST 002-GG, circa 1988 -- 2004; MS170.007.001.031.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - The American South Since 1865: History and Literature, HST 171/CIS 151, Fall 1995; MS170.007.001.031.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - The American South Since 1865, HST 002-GG, Fall 1999; MS170.007.001.031.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Various courses, 1989 -- 2003; MS170.007.001.010.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Various courses, 1991 -- 2000; MS170.007.001.010.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Various courses, Spring 1992 -- Spring 2003; MS170.007.001.010.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Various courses, 1995 -- 2004; MS170.007.001.010.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Various courses and Eyes on the Prize materials, 1998 -- 2000; MS170.007.001.010.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Various courses, 1999; MS170.007.001.010.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Various courses and correspondence, 1999 -- 2000; MS170.007.001.010.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Various courses, 2004 -- 2005; MS170.007.001.010.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Various courses, 2004 -- 2006; MS170.007.001.010.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Other courses, 1976 -- 1983; MS170.007.002; 0.6 Linear Feet 1 partial record carton, 1 legal-sized folder
    This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.
    This series contains materials relating to courses taught by Gill at institutions other than Tufts. Materials include syllabi, class handouts and presentations, course readings, exams, and student papers. The courses include: Introduction to Black History (Howard University, 1976); African American History Since 1865, Comparative Slave Systems, and History of Black America 1877 to Present (University of the District of Columbia, circa 1978); and the Civil War and Reconstruction (Amherst College, 1983).
    - African American History Since 1865, University of the District of Columbia, QH110, circa 1978; MS170.007.002.031.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - The Civil War and Reconstruction, Amherst College, American Studies II, Fall 1983; MS170.007.002.010.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Comparative Slave Systems, University of the District of Columbia, QH 310 01, Spring 1978; MS170.007.002.010.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - History of Black America, 1877--Present, University of the District of Columbia, QH 100 Sec 03, Spring 1978; MS170.007.002.010.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Introduction to Black History, Howard University, 13-006-02, Spring 1976; MS170.007.002.010.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Student papers and review copies, 1974 -- 2007; MS170.007.003; 11 Linear Feet 11 record cartons
    The class papers are student assignments, often graded, written by students for classes taught by Gill. Tufts theses, dissertations and senior special projects are major student works, typically involving original research. The grant proposals and review copies were materials related to Gill's interests that were sent to him by third parties for review.
    - Class papers, 1987 -- 2007; MS170.007.003.001; 4.5 Linear Feet 4 record cartons, 1 partial record carton.
      This series/sub-series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
      This sub-sub-series is arranged alphabetically by title.
      The class papers are student assignments, often graded, written by students for classes taught by Gill.
      - The African American in U.S. History To 1865 papers, 2003; MS170.007.003.001.032.00001; 2 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
      - The African American in U.S. History Since 1865 papers, 1999; MS170.007.003.001.032.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - The African American in U.S. History Since 1865 papers, 2000; MS170.007.003.001.032.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
      - The African American in U.S. History Since 1865 papers and oral histories, 2005; MS170.007.003.001.032.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - The African American in U.S. History Since 1865 papers, 2005 -- 2007; MS170.007.003.001.032.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - The African American in U.S. History Since 1865 oral histories, 2006; MS170.007.003.001.032.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - American Class and Social Inequality papers, 2005 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.032.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 1988; MS170.007.003.001.032.00008; 5 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 10-14)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, circa 1998 -- 1991; MS170.007.003.001.032.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - The American Homefront During World War II oral histories, 1988; MS170.007.003.001.032.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 1991; MS170.007.003.001.032.00011; 2 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 17-18)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, "Black and Blue Poetry", 1991; MS170.007.003.001.032.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 32, Folder 19)
        See related audiocassette in Series 1.
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 2000; MS170.007.003.001.033.00001; 4 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 2000; MS170.007.003.001.033.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.033.00003; 4 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 6-9)
      - The American Homefront During World War II papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.033.00004; 4 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 10-13)
      - The American Homefront During World War II oral history, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.033.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - The American South Since 1865 paper outlines, 1989; MS170.007.003.001.033.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - The American South Since 1865 oral histories, 1992; MS170.007.003.001.033.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 16)
        Includes oral history with Gerald Gill.
      - The American South Since 1865 papers, 2003; MS170.007.003.001.033.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - The American South Since 1865 oral histories, 2005; MS170.007.003.001.034.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - The American South Since 1865 papers, 2005 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.034.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 1987; MS170.007.003.001.034.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1989 -- 1990; MS170.007.003.001.034.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 1990; MS170.007.003.001.034.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1990; MS170.007.003.001.034.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1992 -- 1996; MS170.007.003.001.034.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1995; MS170.007.003.001.034.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1996 -- 1999; MS170.007.003.001.034.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1999 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.034.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 16)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1997; MS170.007.003.001.034.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 1999; MS170.007.003.001.034.00011; 3 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 13-15)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 2000; MS170.007.003.001.034.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 34, Folder 17)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.035.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.035.00002; 3 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 2-4)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 2006; MS170.007.003.001.035.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 2006; MS170.007.003.001.035.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Civil rights movement course papers, 2007; MS170.007.003.001.035.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 7-8)
      - Civil rights oral histories, 2007; MS170.007.003.001.035.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - HST 92A papers, 1989 -- 1991; MS170.007.003.001.035.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - HST 187 papers and reviews, 2006; MS170.007.003.001.035.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Immigration papers, circa 2002; MS170.007.003.001.035.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Internship journals, 1989 -- 2005; MS170.007.003.001.035.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - Paper fragments, circa 1995 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.035.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - Readings course on Reconstruction papers, 2005; MS170.007.003.001.035.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Sports in American History papers, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.001.035.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2001; MS170.007.003.001.035.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2001 -- 2007; MS170.007.003.001.035.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.035.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.001.036.00001; 4 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2005; MS170.007.003.001.036.00002; 4 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 5-8)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2005 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.036.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Sports in American History papers, 2006; MS170.007.003.001.036.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Various papers, 1988 -- 2000; MS170.007.003.001.036.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Various papers, 1990 -- 2000; MS170.007.003.001.036.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Various papers, 2004 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.001.036.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 13)
      - Various papers, 2005; MS170.007.003.001.036.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Tufts theses, dissertations, and senior special projects, 1974 -- 2007; MS170.007.003.002; 6 Linear Feet 5 full record cartons, 2 partial record cartons, 2 legal-sized folders
      This sub-sub-series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
      Tufts theses, dissertations, and senior special projects are arranged alphabetically by title.
      Tufts theses, dissertations and senior special projects are major student works, typically involving original research.
      - "The Accessibility of Higher Education for African Americans," Madeleine McCarthy, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.036.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - "Adolescent Pregnancy and Parenthood in the 1990s: Myths, Reality, and Public Policy," Erica D. Busch, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.036.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - "Affirmative Action," Kenneth S. Tollett Sr., 1999; MS170.007.003.002.036.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - "African American Healthcare Issues," Malika McCray, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.036.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - "African American Protest to the Vietnam War," Rebecca Raymond, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.036.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - "Ain't Nothing Like the Real Thing: The Power of Authenticity Constructions with the Black Imagination," Chinua Thelwell, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.036.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - "Altering the Immigrant City: American Suburbanization and its Impact on the City of Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1840s-1972," Nathaniel Beaudoin, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.036.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - "The American Slave Narrative," Barbara Rodriguez, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.036.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - "The Amoskeag and its City: Power and Protest in Manchester, New Hampshire in the 1840s," Kimberley Frederick, Seminar on Immigration and Urban History, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.037.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - "The Asian American Experience in Ballet," Elizabeth Lee Mochizuki, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.037.00002; 2 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 2-3)
      - "Beyond Name Calling and the Romantic Histories: The Relationship Between African Americans and Jews in New York City, 1973--1992," Nathaniel Klitsberg, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.037.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - "Birth of Consciousness: Activism at Spelman College, 1953--1965," Molly Blank, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.037.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Black pacifism during World War I, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.037.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - "Black Power vs. Revolutionary Intercommunarism," John Stewart, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.037.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Blackside, Inc. internship paper, Eric K. Chapman, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.037.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - "Boston Blacks in the Depression and New Deal," Jeffery Thomas Sammons, 1974; MS170.007.003.002.037.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - "Boston Blacks in the Depression and New Deal," Jeffery Thomas Sammons, 1974; MS170.007.003.002.037.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - "The Boston METCO Program: A Community Perspective, 1966--1976," Gregory R. Staiti, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.037.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - "Breaking the Rules at the Border of Race and Gender: A Discussion on the Intersection of Race and Gender in the Artwork of Elizabeth Catlet, Betye Saar, Judith Baca, and Esther Hernandez," Elizabeth Elvira Garcia, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.037.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - "Breaking the Rules at the Border of Race and Gender: A Discussion on the Intersection of Race and Gender in the Artwork of Elizabeth Catlet, Betye Saar, Judith Baca, and Esther Hernandez," Elizabeth Elvira Garcia, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.037.00012; 2 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 13-14)
      - "Campaign, Coalition, Catastrophe: Black-Jewish Relations in Twentieth Century Chicago," Nicole W. Brodsky, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.037.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - "The Career and Music of Jazz Pianist Wynton Kelly," James P. Clark, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.037.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - "Ceiling and Visibility Limited: Women's Airforce Service Pilots of World War II," Anne E. Doss, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.037.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - "Centering the Margins: A Dialogue Between Three Generations of Cape Verdean Americans Examining the Intersections of Immigration, Labor, Race and Ethnic Identity," Peter Joseph Etish Andrews, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.037.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - "The Changing Ethnicity of Baseball," David Barkin, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.037.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - "Charleston: One Family's Perspective" oral histories, David Garfinkel, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.037.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 20)
      - "Charles W. Chesnutt: Conjuring on the Color Line," Jenelle Walthous, circa 1990; MS170.007.003.002.037.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 21)
      - "Come Experience the World of S and M: Visions of Self-Orientalizing," Gale K. Chang, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.037.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 22)
      - "Compromises and Conflict: The Women of Simmons College and the Emergence of Women's Professions in Early Twentieth Century America," Samantha Fox Morrow, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.037.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - "Conventions, Demonstrations and Urban Renewal: Selling the City of Brotherly Love Through the 2000 Republican National Convention," Sandra Fried, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.037.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 24)
      - "The Clouding of Memory: The Importance of the Brixton Riots 20 Years Later," Christopher Mitchell, 2002; MS170.007.003.002.037.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 25)
      - "Covering an American Pasttime: An Examination of Media Constructions of Race and Ethnicity in Baseball," Benjamin Chang, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.037.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 26)
      - "Creating Communities in the West: Mexican American and African American Migrant Women's Experience in Twentieth Century California," Brianne Peck, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.037.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 27)
      - "The Crisis of Masculinity and Sports," David H. Leach, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.037.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 28)
      - "Death and Life of Malcom X," Stephanie Hunt, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.037.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 29)
      - "The Demands of a New Idiom: Music Language and Participation in the Work of Amiri Baraka, Kamau Brathwaite, and Linton Kwesi Johnson," Amor Kohli, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.037.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 30)
      - "Democratic Road to Socialism and Revolution from Below," Peter Winn and David Ross, 1981; MS170.007.003.002.037.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 31)
      - "Deregulation of the Broadcast Industry and its Effects on Minorities," Vera L. Walker, 1981; MS170.007.003.002.037.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 32)
      - "The Desegregation of the Boston Red Sox," Marci Devlin, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.037.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 33)
      - "The Desegregation of the Boston Red Sox," Marci Devlin, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.037.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 37, Folder 34)
      - "The Desegregation of Boston Schools," Judy Schindler and Caroline Von Fluegge, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.038.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - "The (De)Segregation of the U.S. Education System," Lauren R. White, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.038.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - "Desegregation to Segregation: Public Schools in Norfolk, Virginia," Mary Doyle, 2002; MS170.007.003.002.038.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - "Dick Gregory: A Political and Intellectual Biography, 1958--1972," Adam S. I. Goodman, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.038.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - "A Different Journey: John Brown Russworm, 1799--1851," Sandra R. Sandiford, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.038.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - "Differential Marital Fertility in Holyoke, Massachusetts in 1900," Theodore L. Steinberg, 1983; MS170.007.003.002.038.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - "Disclosing the Backlash on Sexual Harassment," Jerri Shick, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.038.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - "Dishin' It With Alexis" TV show project, Alexis Miller, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.038.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - "Doing for Self!: The Nation of Islam's Temple #11 and its Impact on Social and Economic Development of Boston's African American Community, 1948--1968," Fatimah Abdul-Tawwab, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.038.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - "Dorothy West and the Women-Centered Politics of Black Literary Gentility, 1926--1951", circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.038.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - "The Dusts of Hiroshima Settle on the Classroom: The Atom Bomb and American Education," Dana McLeod, 1990; MS170.007.003.002.038.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - "Eastwood's Western: Reinterpreting the American Myth," J. D. Devan, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.038.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - "Economic and Social Insecurity: The Inconsistencies and Failures of the Welfare System in the U.S.A.," Debbie Kim, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.038.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - "An Effort to Understand the 'Broken Alliance': Black-Jewish Relations from 1963--1978," Stephanie Wolk, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.038.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - "Election 2000: A Historical Analysis and the Implications of a Closely Contested Victory," Moira Poe, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.038.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - "Expanded Opportunities, Limited Equality: The Boundaries of Change for Labor and Work in Boston's Shipyards During World War II," Max Felker-Kantor, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.038.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - "Exploitation of the Black Student Athlete in American Basketball," Khari Brown, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.038.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - "A Family Affair: Stone Bros. Inc. Meets the Business Theorists," Scott Hollander, circa 1990; MS170.007.003.002.038.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - "'Freedom Means a House to Live In': Black Struggle for Equal Housing Opportunities in Greater Boston 1948--1968," Max Felker-Kantor, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.038.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 19)
      - "From Trash Cans to Triage: Strategies and Tactics of the First Year of the New York Young Lords," Jose M. DeJesus, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.038.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 20)
      - "Fighting Back from Behind Barbed Wire: The Life and Legacy of Toshiko Furuta Yonemura, 1935--1947," Teresa M. Wing, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.038.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - "For the Honors of the Cinderpath: The Women's Olympic Games and the Struggle for Control of Women's Competitive Sport, 1890--1929," Erin A. Dromgoole, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.038.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 22)
      - "'Forward Our Girls Go By All Means… But Not Too Fast': Gender, Politics, and Reform in the Ladies Home Journal, 1889--1912," Jenny W. Belknap, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.038.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - "Four Asian American Texts in Their Historical Context: Mrs. Spring Fragrance, Quiet Odyssey, No-No Boy, and Nisei Daughter," Caroline Kim, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.038.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 24)
      - "'Freedom' In Ohio for Gist Freedman," Lois Anderson, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.038.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 25)
      - "From Africa to America: Blacks in Art, Literature, and History", 2001; MS170.007.003.002.038.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 26)
      - "The Future of Higher Education on the West Coast: Could A Predominantly Black University Emerge in Seattle?" L. Scott Larson, 1993; MS170.007.003.002.038.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 27)
      - "Girl of the Month: A History of Women in Broadcast Journalism," Tamara L. Wieder, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.038.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 28)